Violetta Nadbitova

07725003082 | venadbitova@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/violettanadbitova/ | No visa sponsorship required | Salford, United Kingdom | Immediate availability | Geographically mobile

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am developing my career in multimedia and have a diverse international background. I have gained experience in multimedia journalism through my work with an English-speaking newspaper in Russia. I am motivated by hard work and find inspiration in people and their stories. My passion lies in exploring new avenues and gaining firsthand experience in the field of multimedia. Drawing from my diverse background and previous experiences living and working in various countries, I have launched my own podcast called "Diversity Podcast."

KEY SKILLS

Functional expertise: Research, storytelling, video production, journalism, content creation, editing, copywriting, interview, radio production, cross-cultural communication, community outreach, Bilingual (English, Russian), reportage, video and photo editing.

Technical Skills: Microsoft Office / SharePoint, Consultant Plus, Adobe Creative Cloud: Premiere Pro, Audition and Photoshop, Reaper.

EDUCATION

MA in International Journalism - Liverpool John Moores University – Liverpool, UK 2017 – 2018 Modules studied: Journalism Studies, Broadcast Journalism, Advanced UK Broadcast Journalism.

BS in Social Sciences - National Research University Higher School of Economics, Moscow, Russia **2012** – **2017**. **Hidden Employment in Provinces** – National Research University, Uryupinsk, Russia. **Apr 2017** Research focused on the shadow economy sector, specifically self-employment in the Natural Resources sector.

A-Levels: 5 passes at A-B - Elista Multidisciplinary Gymnasium, Russia 2001 - 2012

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PODCASTER MAY 2023 - Present - <u>Diversity Podcast</u>. I single-handedly create, edit, and produce my podcast titled "Diversity Podcast." This show delves into the subjects of diversity and emphasises the significance of embracing one's identity.

WORK EXPERIENCE FEB 2023 - FEB 2023 NINE LIVES MEDIA – Salford, MediaCityUK, UK **EDITOR OCT 2022 - PRESENT** READY-VISA, LONDON, UK - REMOTE

- Editing Global Talent Visa case documents
- Helping with the required documents preparation for visa
- Managing and editing content

FREELANCE PHOTOGRAPHER MAR 2018 - PRESENT VIOLETTANADBITOVA.COM

- Collaborating with different subjects from all walks of life and different age groups, including working with different social groups to lead photography / videography work for personal projects and clients
- · Working with various teams to ensure the subject is prepared for the shoot and that the lighting is correct
- Utilizing photographic best practices to capture both action shots that convey the emotion in human subjects

EUROPEAN CUSTOMER SERVICE ADVISOR APR 2021 - NOV 2022 BET365 - STOKE-ON-TRENT, UK • Brought into

the Customer Team to deliver the highest levels of customer service to a Russian and English speaking customer base, performing a range of different customer service tasks

- Thriving in this fast-paced environment and collaborating with different teams to resolve customer issues ensuring all activities comply with best practices, processes, and procedures
- Developing key relationships across the customer portfolio that are based on trust and geared for longevity

EDITORIAL AND MARKETING ASSISTANT JAN 2021 - MAR 2021 ALT A REVIEW - LONDON - UK

- Supported the creation and publishing of content that resonated with target audiences maintaining tight editorial control of content on various pages
- Edited video and photographic output for distribution across Alt A's social media presence Delivered professional customer service to site subscribers that was based on trust, honesty, and respect

SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER JAN 2020- APR 2020 MIPT, LABORATORY FOR IT EDUCATION DEVELOPMENT - MOSCOW - RUSSIA

- Maximised reach and user engagement through developing engaging social media content, including writing daily news and posts that resonated with target audiences
- Infused powerful messaging across social media channels as well as leading multi-platform awareness campaigns

MULTIMEDIA TRAINEE MAY 2019 - NOV 2019 THE MOSCOW TIMES - MOSCOW - MOSCOW - RUSSIA

- Brought into the Multimedia team at Russia's leading English-language newspaper to produce visual content for national and international audiences
- Collaborated with the team on daily news production as well as creating photo and video reportages ensuring all output aligned with editorial policy and quality standards
- Developed fresh angles to ensure that all contributions and content remained compelling, useful and innovative
- Worked to tight deadlines to conceptualise and write features that met the needs of target audiences

LANGUAGES

Nationality: Russian. Languages: Russian (native); English (Professional proficiency); French (A1)

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Reform Radio - Radio Course, March 2023. Produced and contributed to the live Radio Show - <u>Your Life and Mine</u> **NistratovSchool** - 10+10. Contemporary Documentary Photography and Visual Narrative **Nov 2022** - **Feb 23 Matt**

Black: The Documentary Commitment – Magnum Learn Mar 2022

Localization Essentials – Udacity Aug 2020

TESOL Certificate – International Open Academy Apr 2019

Boris Nemtsov Foundation for Freedom - Boris Nemtsov School of Journalism and Cultural Studies, Prague, CR **Jul 2018 – Aug 2018**

VOLUNTEERING

Media Marketing Manager – Starseed Learning, UK Mar 2021- August 2021

Volunteer - Center for Curative Pedagogics, Moscow, Mar 2017 - Aug 2017

English Tutor – Adaptation and Learning Center for Refugee Children, Moscow, Russia Apr 2016 – Jan 2017